BO CHEN

3545 Northwest 24th Boulevard, Gainesville, Florida, 32605

J (352)328-2874, **≥** bochenuf@gmail.com, **in** LinkedIn Profile

PROFILE

I am a final-year Ph.D. student focusing on privacy-enhanced technologies (e.g., differential privacy) with applications to control systems, networked systems, and learning algorithms. Highly skilled in developing privacy mechanisms for network models, online communication, and multi-modal data; as well as private learning algorithms such as deep learning and federated learning.

SKILLS

Privacy-Enhanced Technology: Differential Privacy.

Network Systems: Disease Spreading Networks, Graph-Based Multiagent Planning Systems.

Privacy Protections for Data: Numerical Data, Symbolic Data (e.g., text).

Private Learning Algorithms: Differentially Private Stochastic Gradient Descent, Federated Learning.

Programming Softwares: Python (TensorFlow, PyTorch, Opacus), MATLAB, CasADi.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Control, Optimization, and Robotics Engineering (CORE) Lab, Gainesville, FL $Graduate\ Research\ Assistant$

 $May\ 2020$ - Present

- Privacy in Disease Spreading Networks: Developed differentially private mechanisms to protect participants' privacy by adding carefully calibrated noise to the weights and basic reproduction number (R_0) of networked SIS/SIR models. Tradeoffs between the level of privacy protections and precision of privatized R_0 were quantified.
- Privacy in Symbolic Data: Developed differentially private mechanisms for logically coherent text sentences. These novel mechanisms offer the capability to produce privacy-preserved sentences in which the logical flow between words is maintained. Analytical and empirical tradeoffs on Hamming distance between original sentences and privatized sentences are quantified, which provides insights into selecting an appropriate level of privacy protection.
- Privacy in Data with Bounded Supports: Developed a differentially private noise-adding mechanism for multivariate data with bounded supports. The proposed mechanism outperforms the existing mechanisms by achieving a reduction of around 35% in the variance of the introduced noise.
- Privacy in Learning Algorithms: Conducted experiments to compare the performance of differentially private machine/federate learning with multi-modal medical data.

Distributed Control of Energy Systems (DiCE) Lab, Gainesville, FL Graduate Student Researcher

Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2020

- Optimization: Developed a novel energy-efficient commercial building heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC) control algorithm. The additional energy savings due to the proposed controller over the baseline algorithm, which has been used in most of the commercial buildings in the US, is up to 30%.
- Data Preprocessing and Analysis: Retrieved outdoor weather data from public databases such as Weather Underground and National Solar Radiation Database, preprocessing it for simulations; Visualized data collected from components of HVAC systems and analyzed their power consumption, aiming to identify potential energy savings.

China National Cereals, Oils and Foodstuffs Corporation, Beijing, China $Control\ Intern$

May 2018 - Aug. 2018

· Programming: Developed Python programs to collect, store, and analyze various metrics received from a remote farm.

EDUCATION

University of Florida, Gainesville, FL

May 2020 - May 2024

Ph.D. - Mechanical Engineering

University of Florida, Gainesville, FL

Aug. 2017 - May 2019

MS - Aerospace Engineering

Northwestern Polytechnical University, Xi'an, China

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2017

BE - Detection, Guidance, and Control Technology